<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learn vCO on vCO Team</title>
    <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Learn vCO on vCO Team</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to create a Microsoft DNS Dynamic Types plug-in ?</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/323-how-to-create-a-microsoft-dns-dynamic-types-plug-in.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/323-how-to-create-a-microsoft-dns-dynamic-types-plug-in.html</guid>
      <description>On the VMware blog I have explained how vRealize Automation Anything as a Service (XaaS) work with Orchestrator and how a vRO plug-in works.
In this tutorial I will walk you through how I managed to implement Microsoft DNS as a service I used for the screenshot examples on that blog including:
 The Microsoft DNS dynamic types plug-in DNS record as a service in vRA DNS record as a blueprint component  This is the first public tutorial on how to create a Dynamic Types plug-in from scratch and the overall methodology used applies to other integrations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to update a Resource Element Script&#39;s Contents using curl</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/322-how-to-update-a-resource-element-script-s-contents-using-curl.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/322-how-to-update-a-resource-element-script-s-contents-using-curl.html</guid>
      <description>In a previous article, I taught you How to retrieve a script Resource from vRO via curl. That can be helpful to some people, but how about updating that script? Easy! Read on&amp;hellip;
This is a super short post since all the tough details were already outlined in the article linked above. So, assuming you already know the ID and name of the script you wish to update, all you need to do is run the following curl command:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to retrieve a script Resource from vRO via curl</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/321-how-to-retrieve-a-script-resource-from-vro-via-curl.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/321-how-to-retrieve-a-script-resource-from-vro-via-curl.html</guid>
      <description>I recently spent time with a customer doing a vRO workshop with them. During the course of the workshop, I was asked how you could retrieve a script that had been stored as a resource element on a vRO server using curl. Well, I had never done that before so I set out to figure it out and was able to provide the solution before I left! Throughout this article, I will be using a vRA 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Disable Storage I/O Stats Collection with PowerCLI or vRO</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/319-how-to-disable-storage-i-o-stats-collection-with-powercli-or-vro.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/319-how-to-disable-storage-i-o-stats-collection-with-powercli-or-vro.html</guid>
      <description>I recently came across a thread asking about how to disable Storage I/O Statistics Collection using PowerCLI. The thread referenced this article by Michael Webster: Disable SIOC IO Metrics Collection For Auto Tiering Storage Systems. In one of the comments, someone asked about using PowerCLI.. Unfortunately there was no answer there so I thought - I might be able to figure this out! With regards to checking that box, I can&amp;rsquo;t say whether it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea or not, my purpose here was just to illustrate how to do it via PowerCLI and vRO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Configure vRA&#39;s Embedded vRO to Allow Domain Account Login</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/312-how-to-configure-vra-s-embedded-vro-to-allow-domain-account-login.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/312-how-to-configure-vra-s-embedded-vro-to-allow-domain-account-login.html</guid>
      <description>Two years ago, I wrote a similar article around vCAC&amp;rsquo;s embedded vCO but a lot has changed since then so those older steps no longer apply. This brief article will quickly walk you through the steps required to allow vRealize Automation 7.0/7.1/7.2&amp;rsquo;s embedded vRealize Orchestrator to allow Active Directory Domain accounts login to the vRO Client.
Pre-Requisites This article assumes the following:
 vRealize Automation 7.0-7.2 is installed and configured (NOTE: This has not been tested with 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to limit number of workflow tokens</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/311-how-to-limit-number-of-workflow-tokens.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/311-how-to-limit-number-of-workflow-tokens.html</guid>
      <description>Each time vRealize Orchestrator (vRO) runs a workflow, a token (workflow execution) is added beneath the workflow in the vRO client. By default vRO will keep up to 100 of these tokens! This may be a slight annoyance to people who are only interested in the last 5-20 runs. This article will shed some light on the configuration options you have available to you.
Tired of seeing too many workflow tokens?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Linux networking with network manager</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/308-configure-linux-networking-with-network-manager.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/308-configure-linux-networking-with-network-manager.html</guid>
      <description>I am working on a project where I need to apply live, permanent networking configuration changes to Linux VMs that may not even have a network configured in the first place.
To do so I am leveraging:
 vSphere guest operations allowing to run commands in the guest OS even if it is not networked yet. NetworkManager / nmcli which provides a command line way to get and set a broad set of network configurations that can be applied immediately and permanently .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging vCenter 6 vAPI REST endpoint</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/307-leveraging-vcenter-6-vapi-rest-endpoint.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/307-leveraging-vcenter-6-vapi-rest-endpoint.html</guid>
      <description>vCenter 6 has introduced an important new feature for anyone interested in Automation and integration : a REST based endpoint providing access to some of the recent functionality such as the tagging service, the content library and transfer service : It is called &amp;ldquo;VMware vCloud Suite SDK&amp;rdquo; and codenamed vAPI. In addition to the REST API it provides language bindings for Java, Python, .NET, Perl and Ruby. If you want to know more about vAPI you can read the blog article I wrote on the VMware CTO Ambassadors blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synchronize Presentation Settings from embedded workflow</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/306-synchronize-presentation-settings-from-embedded-workflow.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/306-synchronize-presentation-settings-from-embedded-workflow.html</guid>
      <description>VMware&amp;rsquo;s vRealize Orchestrator (vRO) is all about modular, reusable components. Many times you wish to call an existing workflow from your own custom workflow but don&amp;rsquo;t want to manually re-create all the different presentation settings. It&amp;rsquo;s not such a big task if there are only one or two workflows, but how about when there are 10+ ? Good news is that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to! This quick little video demonstrates how to Synchronize the Presentation of an embedded workflow to your own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating json objects in Orchestrator</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/305-creating-json-objects-in-orchestrator.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/305-creating-json-objects-in-orchestrator.html</guid>
      <description>Recently I saw a pair of articles by @RoeyAzroel on vRO XML &amp;amp; JSON Gotcha! - Part 1 and Part 2. This reminded me that I had some sample code that I refer to when working with json as well so figured I would share here.
Be sure you know about the JSON object and its .parse and .stringify methods since they do not appear anywhere in the Orchestrator&amp;rsquo;s API explorer or documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postman &#43; vRO = HTTP-REST Plug-in Operations</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/304-postman-vro-http-rest-plug-in-operations.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/304-postman-vro-http-rest-plug-in-operations.html</guid>
      <description>In a previous article, I stepped through the process of working with vRealize Orchestrator&amp;rsquo;s (vRO) REST API using the RestClient add-on for FireFox. This was before I was introduced to my new favorite REST client: POSTMAN! @postmanclient In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll provide a little detail on an approach you can use to improve your work with REST APIs and consuming them with Orchestrator&amp;rsquo;s REST plug-in. Throughout the article, I will use a FreeNAS 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Log plug-ins HTTP communications</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/303-log-plug-ins-http-communications.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/303-log-plug-ins-http-communications.html</guid>
      <description>A lot of the Orchestrator plug-ins use the Apache HTTP client to communicate with the target hosts. You may want to log the HTTP communications for many purposes:
 Understanding how vCO does the API calls Troubleshoot a problem with a target host Re-engineering an existing call with capturing it, changing it as you like and use it via the REST or SOAP plug-in Brag you have found an &amp;ldquo;Onyx&amp;rdquo; like functionality for most Orchestrated products  This article will guide you on how to log these calls to a file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plug-in Generator v2 advanced techniques</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/302-create-a-plug-in-for-orchestrator.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/302-create-a-plug-in-for-orchestrator.html</guid>
      <description>In previous tutorials we created inventory object types, their children objects, workflows to operate these that we packaged for our end users.
In this tutorial we are going to create an orchestrator plug-in to list vCO / vRO workflows ! You may wonder why doing so ?
This is a good use case for leveraging some of the more advanced features of the plug-in generator v2 to handle complex REST APIs and improving performance when needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a plug-in for a REST based web service in minutes - Part 4</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/301-create-a-plug-in-for-a-rest-based-web-service-in-minutes-part-4.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/301-create-a-plug-in-for-a-rest-based-web-service-in-minutes-part-4.html</guid>
      <description>In part 1 and part 2 we created the inventory objects, in part 3 we created methods for this objects and ran a generic workflow to run these methods.
In this article we will create workflows for calling these methods, include them in a package with all the plug-in configuration to ship it to our end users.
Creating the workflows The invoke workflows in the plug-in facilitate running REST operations. End users and or external system will expect simpler workflows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a plug-in for a REST based web service in minutes - Part 3</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/300-create-a-plug-in-for-a-rest-based-web-service-in-minutes-part-3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/300-create-a-plug-in-for-a-rest-based-web-service-in-minutes-part-3.html</guid>
      <description>Part 1 of the plug-in generator v2 series covered how to create new plug-in inventory types, part 2 how to create their child object types. This part will focus on how to define object methods and associated workflows. Having Orchestrator inventory types is a necessity to use with vRealize Automation (formerly vCAC) Advanced Service Designer. Once you have these inventory objects you may wonder how to use these in workflows. This is what this article covers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a plug-in for a REST based web service in minutes - Part 2</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/299-create-a-plug-in-for-a-rest-based-web-service-in-minutes-part-2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/299-create-a-plug-in-for-a-rest-based-web-service-in-minutes-part-2.html</guid>
      <description>In the part 1 I walk through step by step to create a plug-in object type leveraging the Plug-in Generator version 2.
In this article I will demonstrate one of the new feature of this version 2 : Create a child object type.
Having the plug-in inventory organized in a tree view allows to represent most of the objects hierarchies found in applications APIs.
Resuming from part 1 I need to create a vNIC object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a plug-in for a REST based web service in minutes - part 1</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/298-create-a-plug-in-for-a-rest-web-service-in-minutes.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/298-create-a-plug-in-for-a-rest-web-service-in-minutes.html</guid>
      <description>In a previous article I have explained how Dynamic Types work and how these are very useful to create a vCO / vRO plugin that will enable the XaaS capabilitites of vCAC / vRA.
Then explained how to build your own twitter plug-in using the plug-in generator package. I have now extended the capabilities of the plug-in generator and will attempt to demonstrate these in this new series of articles. This article use NSX as the orchestrated endpoint but following the explanation included on this tutorial you should be able to get it to work with many REST web service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use PowerShell to start an Orchestrator Workflow</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/297-how-to-use-powershell-to-start-an-orchestrator-workflow-2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/297-how-to-use-powershell-to-start-an-orchestrator-workflow-2.html</guid>
      <description>Okay now I have provided Python and [perl](/articles/learn-vco/296-how-to-use-perl-to-start-an-orchestrator-workflow.html&amp;quot; rel=&amp;ldquo;alternate) articles to start a vRealize Orchestrator (vRO / vCO) workflow via it&amp;rsquo;s REST API so now it&amp;rsquo;s time for a PowerShell script. For this article, I followed the same format as the previous two BUT provided the option to call the script with command line parameters! You may download the script in this article from my vroClientScripts Repository on GitHub.
The Script The following code should be saved as something like runWorkflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use perl to start an Orchestrator Workflow</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/296-how-to-use-perl-to-start-an-orchestrator-workflow.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/296-how-to-use-perl-to-start-an-orchestrator-workflow.html</guid>
      <description>In a previous article, I taught you how to explore and use the REST API to start a Workflow using a generic browser based REST Client. In this article, I will provide a perl based example of running the &amp;ldquo;Create a Record&amp;rdquo; workflow that was created in Part 2 of my SQL Plug-in Dynamic Types Simple CMDB for vCAC article. I have barely more experience with perl than Python so this will be another very short article!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use Python to start an Orchestrator Workflow</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/295-how-to-use-python-to-start-an-orchestrator-workflow.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/295-how-to-use-python-to-start-an-orchestrator-workflow.html</guid>
      <description>In a previous article, I taught you how to explore and use the REST API to start a Workflow using a generic browser based REST Client. In this article, I will provide a Python based example of running the &amp;ldquo;Create a Record&amp;rdquo; workflow that was created in Part 2 of my SQL Plug-in Dynamic Types Simple CMDB for vCACarticle. Since I&amp;rsquo;m not even close to being proficient with Python, this will be a very short article!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Plug-in &#43; DynamicTypes = Simple CMDB for vCAC - Part 3</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/294-sql-plug-in-dynamictypes-simple-cmdb-for-vcac-part-3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/294-sql-plug-in-dynamictypes-simple-cmdb-for-vcac-part-3.html</guid>
      <description>Welcome back! This is the third article of a multi-part series that steps you through the process of exposing our workflows from the last article to vRealize Automation&amp;rsquo;s (vRA) Advanced Service Designer (ASD).
Introduction This third article will cover the following topics:
 How to add the simple CMDB to vRealize Automation&amp;rsquo;s Advanced Service Designer Add a Day 2 operation to delete an Asset from our table  Future article will cover the following topic:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Addresses in Range</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/293-get-addresses-in-range.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/293-get-addresses-in-range.html</guid>
      <description>vRealize Orchestrator (vRO) is frequently used with Network related automation which may involve working with IP Addresses. From an end user perspective, it is nice to specify a range of addresses such as 192.168.1.1-192.168.1.100 rather than having to specify all addresses. I found some simple Javascript in this Converting IP Addresses article that is easily adapted to vRO. You can use the code included in this article to either return an array of addresses in the range specified, or simplify it by returning the total number of addresses in the range.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Plug-in &#43; DynamicTypes = Simple CMDB for vCAC - Part 2</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/292-sql-plug-in-dynamictypes-simple-cmdb-for-vcac-part-2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/292-sql-plug-in-dynamictypes-simple-cmdb-for-vcac-part-2.html</guid>
      <description>Welcome back! This is the second article of a multi-part series that steps you through the process of mapping a SQL table into vRealize Orchestrator, building out a DynamicTypes plug-in inventory based on that table, then exposing it to vRealize Automation&amp;rsquo;s Advanced Service Designer (ASD). In the first article, we got our database table mapped using the SQL Plug-in and generated some CRUD workflows.
Introduction Let&amp;rsquo;s build a simple Dynamic Types plug-in around our SQL Table that we created in our previous article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Plug-in &#43; DynamicTypes = Simple CMDB for vCAC - Part 1</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/291-sql-plug-in-dynamictypes-simple-cmdb-for-vcac-part-1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/291-sql-plug-in-dynamictypes-simple-cmdb-for-vcac-part-1.html</guid>
      <description>This multi-part series will step you through the process of mapping a Microsoft SQL Server table into vRealize Orchestrator, building out a DynamicTypes plug-in inventory based on that table (using my workflow package), then exposing it to vRealize Automation&amp;rsquo;s Advanced Service Designer (ASD).
Introduction vRealize Automation (vRA) features an Advanced Service Designer (ASD) that allows for you to offer nearly anything as a service (XaaS). In order to take advantage of that feature, it requires a vRealize Orchestrator (vRO) Inventory object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Input Values Based on other Inputs</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/290-dynamic-input-values-based-on-other-inputs.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/290-dynamic-input-values-based-on-other-inputs.html</guid>
      <description>A frequent requirement when performing orchestration tasks is to have input fields interdependent. For example, if I input XYZ into the first input, I want the second input to be relevant to XYZ. In the past, I have frequently done such workflows where you select a Datacenter for the first input, then the second input would present a list of Datastores (or VMs or Clusters or Hosts). In this tutorial, I&amp;rsquo;m going to do something a little different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extend Automation Center with F5 AFM using vCO &#43; Dynamic Types </title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/289-extend-automation-center-with-f5-afm-using-vco-dynamic-types.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/289-extend-automation-center-with-f5-afm-using-vco-dynamic-types.html</guid>
      <description>My colleague, Chris Slater at defined by software has published an article on how to extend VMware Automation Center (vCAC) with F5 firewall functionality. I usually do not cross post articles but this one is worth mentioning since it is a real world example on how to leverage vCAC + vCO + Dynamic Types + third party API.
The first part of the article explains the different options available to automate F5 including the F5 plug-in for vCO, PowerShell, the big IP CLI, the SOAP and REST APIs and give an overview of the solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extend vCAC 6 IaaS Lifecycle with vCO introduction video</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/286-extend-vcac-6-iaas-lifecycle-with-vco.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/286-extend-vcac-6-iaas-lifecycle-with-vco.html</guid>
      <description>Last year I have created an extensibility package to simplify and automate the steps necessary to extend the vCAC IaaS lifecycle process with calling out vCO workflows. While this was mainly aimed at accelerating Proof of Concepts it has been since then broadly adopted in production environments. Since vCAC 6.0 it is part of the product and available for vCAC 5.2 as a separate download.
Since this is now becoming a very hot topic I am including here a very useful extensibility introduction video that was released by my colleagues from tech marketing almost three months ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use the REST API to Resume a Failed Workflow</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/284-how-to-use-the-rest-api-to-resume-a-failed-workflow.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/284-how-to-use-the-rest-api-to-resume-a-failed-workflow.html</guid>
      <description>One of the relatively new 5.x features of vCenter Orchestrator (vCO) is the ability to Enable a workflow to resume on failure. Essentially, this means that a workflow could fail 1/2 or 3/4 the way through and you could go and tell vCO to resume that workflow, perhaps after fixing whatever issue caused it to fail in the first place, rather than start a fresh instance of the workflow.
Introduction   As noted in the intro snippet, vCO now has the ability to let you resume a failed workflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Types tutorial : Implement your own Twitter plug-in without any scripting</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/282-dynamic-types-tutorial-implement-your-own-twitter-plug-in-without-any-scripting.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/282-dynamic-types-tutorial-implement-your-own-twitter-plug-in-without-any-scripting.html</guid>
      <description>In a previous article I have explained how the vCO dynamic Types allow to simplify the development of vCO plug-ins and how these are leveraged by VMware vCloud Automation Center XaaS. It is now time to experiment with creating a plugin with leveraging the Dynamic Types plug-in generator package.
Warning: You can do it without Java development experience and without having to write a single line of scripting !
As a first step download the Dynamic Types plug-in generator package from VMware communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling VMware vCloud Automation Center XaaS with vCO dynamic types</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/281-enabling-vcloud-automation-center-xaas-with-vco-dynamic-types.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/281-enabling-vcloud-automation-center-xaas-with-vco-dynamic-types.html</guid>
      <description>You may have noticed that the vCO 5.5.1 release notes are listing a new feature called &amp;ldquo;Dynamic Types&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Workflow developers are now able to explore the new Dynamic Types which currently is being shipped with Beta quality. They can easily extend vCenter Orchestrator plug-ins by adding their custom types accessible from the scripting API. New types become available in the inventory right after creation and they could be directly leveraged from the vCAC ASD context as part of the cloud provisioning process and XaaS definition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Configure vCAC&#39;s Embedded vCO To Allow Domain Account Login</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/280-how-to-configure-vcac-s-embedded-vco-to-allow-domain-account-login.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/280-how-to-configure-vcac-s-embedded-vco-to-allow-domain-account-login.html</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re reading this article, it may be because you have installed vCloud Automation Center (vCAC) and are interested in using an account other than administrator@vsphere.local to login to the embedded vCenter Orchestrator (vCO) server. By default, the vCO Server uses a &amp;ldquo;vcoadmins&amp;rdquo; group in the &amp;ldquo;vsphere.local&amp;rdquo; domain provided by the SSO server that vCAC was configured to use. This short tutorial will step you through a pretty basic configuration where I have just deployed a vCAC 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to allow the vCO Appliance to write files to a Windows CIFS share</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/278-how-to-allow-the-vco-appliance-to-write-files-to-a-windows-cifs-share.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/278-how-to-allow-the-vco-appliance-to-write-files-to-a-windows-cifs-share.html</guid>
      <description>A frequent question around vCenter Orchestrator is: Can I read/write to shared folders? The answer is always yes, but the documentation may be difficult to find - especially when you are referring to a Windows share - aka CIFS in samba and *nix mounting terminology. Read on to learn EXACTLY what you need to do to allow your vCO server to read/write to a Windows Share!
Overview: vCO allows limited access to its local filesystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware released vCenter Orchestrator 5.5.1</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/279-vmware-released-vcenter-orchestrator-5-5-1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/279-vmware-released-vcenter-orchestrator-5-5-1.html</guid>
      <description>This week VMware released vCenter Orchestrator 5.5.1. While this is not a major new release it contains a lot of new features focusing on making vCO content development easier. Also important is a list of deprecated features.
Protocol plug-ins are now included The days where vCO was mainly used to automate vCenter are over. vCO integrates with many third party applications using generic protocol based plug-ins. In previous releases you had to find the latest release, download the plug-ins and install these.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Change AD:UserGroup Scope and Type</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/277-how-to-change-ad-usergroup-scope-and-type.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/277-how-to-change-ad-usergroup-scope-and-type.html</guid>
      <description>The AD plug-in for vCenter Orchestrator (vCO) allows for the creation of AD:UserGroup objects as well as the management of its members. A missing option though is to define the type of Group to create. Read on to learn how I came up with a workflow that allows you to change the group to any group type and scope you like.
Research The first thing I did is use the workflow from the How to get Active Directory User Attributes article to create a simlar workflow for UserGroups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with vCO and vCHS</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/276-getting-started-with-vco-and-vchs.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/276-getting-started-with-vco-and-vchs.html</guid>
      <description>vCloud Hybrid Service (vCHS) is backed by vCloud Director. What does this mean? Well, it means that once you have defined 1 or more Virtual Data Centers, and VMware releases an updated vCD plug-in, you will have access to a vCloud Director Organization! Why is that good and what is the point of this post? Well, in short, this means you can use vCenter Orchestrator (vCO) to do some automation within your vCHS Virtual Data Centers!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get Active Directory User Attributes</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/273-how-to-get-active-directory-user-properties.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/273-how-to-get-active-directory-user-properties.html</guid>
      <description>Have you ever had the need to get some attributes of your Active Directory user account? Perhaps Manager for an approval, maybe direct reports, etc&amp;hellip; but not sure how to work with the AD:User object in vCO&amp;hellip; Well here&amp;rsquo;s a great little snippet that can help you quickly identify the available information attached to the AD:User account you specify.
Show AD User Info  Simply place the following script into a scriptable task in a new workflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging the Guest Script Manager package</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/272-leveraging-the-guest-script-manager-package.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/272-leveraging-the-guest-script-manager-package.html</guid>
      <description>Running commands or scripts in VM guest is something that has been done with vCO for quite a while using different mechanisms. A popular way was to use the VIX plug-in for vCO. This plug-in is not needed anymore since the VIX functionality is part of the vCenter API since vCenter 5.0 and there are guest operations workflows to copy a script and run it into a VM guest OS since vCO 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code snippet : Find a workflow by name</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/271-code-snippet-find-a-workflow-by-name.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/271-code-snippet-find-a-workflow-by-name.html</guid>
      <description>vCenter Orchestrator references workflows by ID and allows to have multiple workflows with the same name. If the workflows you are calling have a unique name you can write a vCO wrapper to find a workflow by name with the following code.
Input: wfName (string)
Output: wfByName (Workflow)
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13  var workflows = Server.findAllForType(&amp;#34;Workflow&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;c.name=&amp;#39;&amp;#34;+wfName+&amp;#34;&amp;#39;&amp;#34;); var wfByName = null; if (workflows !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Enable vCO 5.1.x to log API requests</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/270-how-to-enable-vco-51x-to-log-api-requests.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/270-how-to-enable-vco-51x-to-log-api-requests.html</guid>
      <description>When working with new integrations that utilize the vCenter Orchestrator (vCO) REST API you may want additional logging on the vCO side to see what is happening. I came across this need on a recent project. By default, vCO is logging workflow and webview activities but not API calls. This short article walks you through the steps necessary to enable such logging.
The following steps will enable additional logging on your vCO server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run a program in guest from vCloud Automation Center</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/263-run-a-program-in-guest-from-vcloud-automation-center-.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/263-run-a-program-in-guest-from-vcloud-automation-center-.html</guid>
      <description>vCloud Automation Center is the VMware hybrid cloud self-service provisioning portal. It can be customized to extend its OOTB functionality. The following tutorial shows how from the vSphere web client create a menu operation to run a program in a guest or how to do it automatically once the VM has been provisioned. This does not involve any scripting !
Prerequisites vCenter Orchestrator configured with:
 vCenter plug-in (with the same host used in vCAC) vCAC plug-in 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with vCloud Automation Center IaaS entities</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/269-working-with-vcloud-automation-center-infrastructure-as-a-service-entities.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/269-working-with-vcloud-automation-center-infrastructure-as-a-service-entities.html</guid>
      <description>vCloud Automation Center has several constructs such as blueprints, business groups, reservations to manage the virtual machines lifecycle and governance policies.
While most customers will use vCloud Automation Center out of the box some have several use cases for automation and integration. This is where vCenter Orchestrator comes into the picture.
The vCloud Automation Center Infrastructure as a service data model (vCAC IaaS) vCAC IaaS has an extensible model consisting of different metamodels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use the REST API to Start a Workflow</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/268-how-to-use-the-rest-api-to-start-a-workflow.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/268-how-to-use-the-rest-api-to-start-a-workflow.html</guid>
      <description>It seems everyday the interest in vCenter Orchestrator (vCO) is growing. I love this because it brings more and more use cases to our attention. One such use case is the need to call vCO workflows via its REST API. In order to keep this article generic, but useful, I will work with the free RESTClient plug-in/add-on for Firefox as the client. The general process here will be similar to what you may need to do from your software or portal to integrate with vCO&amp;rsquo;s REST API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use the SOAPInterceptor to see the SOAP Header and Body</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/267-how-to-use-the-soapinterceptor-to-see-the-soap-header-and-body.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/267-how-to-use-the-soapinterceptor-to-see-the-soap-header-and-body.html</guid>
      <description>On a recent project, I was having trouble figuring out why invoking a SOAP operation kept failing with the vCO SOAP plug-in. The inputs I was providing appeared to be correct and worked just fine with soapUI. This short tutorial will teach you how to use the SOAPInterceptor to display the Header and Body that the SOAP plug-in is sending.
SOAP Operation Auto-Generated Workflow   A typical Invoke Operation workflow looks similar to the above image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making vCO Workflow Wrappers</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/266-making-vco-workflow-wrappers.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/266-making-vco-workflow-wrappers.html</guid>
      <description>A vCO workflow wrapper is a set of workflow tasks that are added at the beginning of a workflow in order to take string values and look up a more complex data type or pre-defining inputs using attributes. You may have done these in the past already in vCO. Some examples would be finding a virtual machine by name or finding an Active Directory user by email address.
If you&amp;rsquo;re running the vCO workflow from within the vCO client or vSphere web client, you probably don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry about this as both of those tools understand the complex data types that come with plugins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to run a Perl Script from a vCenter Orchestrator Workflow</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/265-how-to-run-a-perl-script-from-a-vcenter-orchestrator-workflow.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/265-how-to-run-a-perl-script-from-a-vcenter-orchestrator-workflow.html</guid>
      <description>PERL Logo   The goal of this tutorial is to create a simple workflow with a single string input that will be passed to a locally hosted Perl script for execution. The results of the script will be returned to vCO and stored in the workflow output. This could come in handy if you have existing systems that already have Perl based management scripts and you wish to incorporate their automation into your Orchestration policies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Supported Hardware Versions from Cluster</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/261-get-supported-hardware-versions-from-cluster.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/261-get-supported-hardware-versions-from-cluster.html</guid>
      <description>Get Supported Hardware Schema   Quite some time ago I had the need to retrieve the supported HW versions for an environment.. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember what the project was, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t terribly important so I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother digging deeper to figure things out - I just worked around the issue. Last month William Lam posted an article on how to do this with PERL.
In this article Which Virtual Hardware Versions (VM Compatibility) Are Supported In vSphere?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remove computer from AD using vCO during vCAC Decommission</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/259-remove-computer-from-ad-using-vco-during-vcac-decommission.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/259-remove-computer-from-ad-using-vco-during-vcac-decommission.html</guid>
      <description>As vCloud Automation Center (vCAC) gains traction, so too does the need for details on how to extend it using vCenter Orchestrator (vCO). I have kept an eye out for good articles on vCAC and just saw a great one at the DailyHypervisor.com blog around Adding a computer account to Active Directory OU. This is something that we had done for LifeCycleManager (LCM) quite some time back and feel it is a good candidate for a vCO-centeric article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enable vCenter Orchestrator (vCO) to read and write Excel files</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/257-enable-vcenter-orchestrator-vco-to-read-and-write-excel-files.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/257-enable-vcenter-orchestrator-vco-to-read-and-write-excel-files.html</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this article is to provide readers with instructions on how to give vCO the ability to read and write Microsoft Excel files (xls / xlsx). Yes, it is 2013 yet there are plenty of reasons why organizations might still be using an Excel spreadsheet instead of a database table.. We won&#39;t dwell on that here, instead we&#39;ll focus on providing those organizations with a step-by-step guide to provide such functionality to vCenter Orchestrator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vCloud Director catalog replication</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/254-vcloud-director-catalog-replication.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/254-vcloud-director-catalog-replication.html</guid>
      <description>vCloud Director has a nice feature allowing to organize vApps into catalogs. If like me you need to replicate these catalog across organization or even different vCloud hosts you may find your solution here.
I have written a solution to do it a long time ago but never had the time to release it publicly. It is now done and here are the features.
FeaturesThis package comes with a rich set of features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extend vCloud Director with service builder</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/253-extend-vcloud-director-with-service-builder.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/253-extend-vcloud-director-with-service-builder.html</guid>
      <description>In a previous article I explained how we could extend vCloud Director with vCenter Orchestrator and then provided a full implementation. This was using the vCloud Director blocking tasks and notifications feature which allow to extend existing vCoud Director operations.
vCloud Director 5.1 introduced a new feature called API extensions which basically allows a cloud provider to extend the vCloud Director API with custom services with leveraging VMware or third party applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FREE VMware vCenter Orchestrator Instructional Videos</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/252-free-vmware-vcenter-orchestrator-instructional-videos.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/252-free-vmware-vcenter-orchestrator-instructional-videos.html</guid>
      <description>VMware education has released a series of vCenter Orchestrator instructional videos.
These short instructional videos, between 5 and 20 minutes in length and presented by VMware Senior Technical Trainer Brian Watrous, cover the following topics:
Introducing vCenter Orchestrator Overview : Introduction of the features and benefits of vCenter Orchestrator. Introducing vCenter Orchestrator Demo : This video demonstrates using a vCenter Orchestrator workflow to gather information. Installing and Configuring vCenter Orchestrator : This video covers the different ways to install and configure vCenter Orchestrator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create your own vCloud Download lossless vApp Template workflow in less than 5 minutes</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/250-create-your-own-vcloud-download-lossless-vapp-template-workflow-in-less-than-5-minutes.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/250-create-your-own-vcloud-download-lossless-vapp-template-workflow-in-less-than-5-minutes.html</guid>
      <description>vCloud Director 5.1 has some new features, one of them allows to keep vApp Templates information that are by default discarded. My colleague William Lam covers this very well in this article. If you think this would be good to have this functionality as a workflow then you can have it in about 5 minutes with creating it on your own.
First thing is there is no out of the box workflow that download a lossless vApp Template but there is one to download a vApp Template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code snippets : Using vCloud Director object metadata</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/249-code-snippets-using-vcloud-director-object-metadata.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/249-code-snippets-using-vcloud-director-object-metadata.html</guid>
      <description>Setting metadata on vCloud Director objects is a convenient way to extend their properties with whatever information you need to attach to these. This is very useful to include information on the object lifecycle or to reference other objects. For example I like to reference the vApp Template a vApp was issued from with adding a &#34;vAppTemplateReference&#34; metadata. Another use of the metadata is that you can search for these using the query service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere 5.1 Web client - The single pane of glass I always wanted</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/248-vsphere-51-web-client-the-single-pane-of-glass-i-always-wanted.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/248-vsphere-51-web-client-the-single-pane-of-glass-i-always-wanted.html</guid>
      <description>If you were at VMworld, during Steve Herrod (VMware CTO) session you could answer in real time to some questions. One of them was Over the next 3 years, how do you plan to manage your hardware infrastructure for your VMware environment ? Primarily from:
vCenter : 62%A converged hardware management tool: 32 %Existing element management tools: 6%It is a good thing most of you want to, it is even better that the vSphere 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage Services on your ESXi Hosts with vCO</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/240-manage-services-on-your-esxi-hosts-with-vco.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/240-manage-services-on-your-esxi-hosts-with-vco.html</guid>
      <description>We&#39;ve all seen that vCenter Orchestrator (vCO) is quite powerful in automating many aspects of your Infrastructure through the variety of specific and generic plug-ins. While there are hundreds of workflows and actions for vCenter included in a clean install of vCO, they simply don&#39;t cover every single thing you may want to do. One such example has come up a few times in the VMware Communities: Managing Services. The following article will walk you through creating a simple workflow that allows you to manage services on a specified ESXi (VC:HostSystem) server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging the VMware vCloud Director query service</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/239-leveraging-the-vmware-vcloud-director-query-service.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/239-leveraging-the-vmware-vcloud-director-query-service.html</guid>
      <description>With the release of vCloud director 1.5 a new important API feature was introduced : the query service. Quoting the &#34;What&#39;s new&#34; whitepaper:
VMware vCloud Director 1.5 also introduces a VMware vCloud API query service,
which can significantly improve developer efficiency, by minimizing the number of API requests and the amount
of data transferred for an API client to obtain needed information. Example query parameters include sorting
and ordering, pagination, filtering, projection, and expressions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pimp my vCenter Orchestrator Virtual Appliance</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/234-pimp-my-vcenter-orchestrator-virtual-appliance.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/234-pimp-my-vcenter-orchestrator-virtual-appliance.html</guid>
      <description>If you like the VMware vCenter Orchestrator (vCO) Appliance because it is easy to deploy, configure and use then you may want to improve it with enabling additional features.
I like very much the vCO appliance but I recognize it has a few shortcomings:
The vCO web start client does not work well on Mac since it does not preserve the client preferences.I am missing local shell control and live logs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vCloud Director Custom Deploy vApp Workflow</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/230-vcloud-director-custom-deploy-vapp-workflow.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/230-vcloud-director-custom-deploy-vapp-workflow.html</guid>
      <description>The overall goal of the Custom Deploy vApp workflow is to provide a single call workflow that is capable of instantiating a vApp Template from vCloud Director (vCD) and performing a number of operations on the resulting vApp before actually deploying and powering it on. The workflow is intended to be an example and starting point for deployments that require any or all of these features. It can also be called via 3rd party connectors using the vCenter Orchestrator SOAP API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vCloud Director blocking tasks and notifications integration with vCO implementation</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/224-vcloud-director-blocking-tasks-and-notifications-integration-with-vco-implementation.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/224-vcloud-director-blocking-tasks-and-notifications-integration-with-vco-implementation.html</guid>
      <description>You may already have seen the theory on how to extend vCloud Director capabilities with vCenter Orchestrator, you may even have completed the first steps to do it following this tutorial. What about having a complete real use case implementation example such as a vApp Approval, adding Windows VM in Active Directory ? It is now available.
The goal of publishing this package is to give a good starting point implementation with working examples that can be adapted for other requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building your custom cloud portal - Knowing when to use the vCloud API and the vCenter Orchestrator web service</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/198-building-your-custom-cloud-when-to-use-the-vcloud-api-or-the-vcenter-orchestrator-web-service.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/198-building-your-custom-cloud-when-to-use-the-vcloud-api-or-the-vcenter-orchestrator-web-service.html</guid>
      <description>My team and I have helped customers to build private and public clouds using vCenter Orchestrator for the last 5 years. Adding vCloud Director in the picture tremendously helps with providing customers a scalable standardized cloud solution. Most people will think at orchestration as a single entry point on top of the cloud when in fact for several use cases it is recommended to have vCloud Director and vCenter Orchestrator running side by side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code snippets :  Use vCenter Orchestrator API explorer to write your own custom getGuestCustomization workflow</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/217-code-snippets-use-the-api-explorer-to-write-your-own-custom-workflows.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/217-code-snippets-use-the-api-explorer-to-write-your-own-custom-workflows.html</guid>
      <description>The vCenter Orchestrator plug-ins are coming with a lot of built in workflows and action scripts. The first thing to do when looking for functionality is to browse the library or use the search filter to find these.
If you do not get exactly what you are looking for, there are chances that some of the existing workflows and actions will contain close enough examples. If you do not find any of these you can still use the API explorer to create your own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unattended deployment of vCenter Orchestrator Appliance</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/211-unnattended-deployment-of-vcenter-orchestrator-appliance.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/211-unnattended-deployment-of-vcenter-orchestrator-appliance.html</guid>
      <description>The vCO appliance makes it very easy to deploy vCenter Orchestrator in minutes. My colleague William Lam went a bit further with providing a script that let you pre-define a lot of the configuration settings.
The script leverage the OVF format to set a number of parameters such as the appliance network settings, placement on the virtual infrastructure datastores and network.
You can find out more about it here.
I am looking forward to see more vCO articles from William since he has a very successful VMware scripting blog with a lot of interesting articles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code snippets : Change the name of a vCloud Director organization</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/208-code-snippets-change-the-name-of-a-vcloud-director-organization.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/208-code-snippets-change-the-name-of-a-vcloud-director-organization.html</guid>
      <description>Sometimes the user interfaces are limiting you by design. The APIs are often more permissive and if you know what you are doing you can do great things.
Previously we showed you how to hot clone vCloud Director vApps. We even did a video tutorial for it. Now it is time to do something else the vCloud Director User Interface will not let you do : rename an organization.
My test org has my name so my colleagues know it is mine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to handle vCenter Orchestrator logs?</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/199-how-to-handle-vcenter-orchestrator-logs.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/199-how-to-handle-vcenter-orchestrator-logs.html</guid>
      <description>vCenter Orchestrator uses a powerful log service. This article explains the basics of this service and possible configuration changes.
This article will identify the log files currently in use for a typical vCO server installation. Additionally, it will address the following areas of interest:
Server Log rollover control: MaxFileSize and MaxBackupIndexEnable REST call logging in the vCloud Director Plug-inEnable logging to a SYSLOG serverSetting the server and all components to debug modeThe vCenter Orchestrator application server log files are located in install_directory\app- server\server\vmo\log</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing Your First VMware vCO Workflow Video Series</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/207-developing-your-first-vmware-vco-workflow-video-series.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/207-developing-your-first-vmware-vco-workflow-video-series.html</guid>
      <description>One of our contributing authors, Sergio Sanchez, has just published a three-part video series on Developing your first VMware vCO Workflow. In this series, Sergio steps you through the process of creating a new workflow to power on a VM and send e-mail from scratch. A couple library actions, a decision box, scriptable tasks, and error handling will be used throughout the series. The actions taken during this video series will be common across nearly all custom workflow development you perform in the future so it serves as a great basis to get you started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code snippets : Create your database plug-in</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/203-code-snippets-create-your-database-plug-in.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/203-code-snippets-create-your-database-plug-in.html</guid>
      <description>Need vCO to fetch some data from a database for integration purposes ? There is an easy solution with creating a plug-in ...
Jerg Lew wrote an excellent article on the different options to integrate vCO with a database here. Creating a hibernate based plug-in is definitely the best way to map a database as vCO objects but it is a lot of effort and can get quite complex.
Since there is another much simpler way to create a database plug-in (with read only rights on the database) I thought I should share it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With Perspectives Webview</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/192-getting-started-with-perspectives-webview.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/192-getting-started-with-perspectives-webview.html</guid>
      <description>Getting started with Perspectives WebviewIf you have been following VMware vCenter Orchestrator (vCO) for a while, it is likely that you have already seen the Perspectives webview in action. It has been used in one or more vCO demos as a web-based interface to launch a specific set of workflows. A web-based interface for launching workflows is a common requirement in organizations and likely a more secure method.
What is Perspectives?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code snippets : Change the name of a workflow run</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/201-code-snippets-change-the-name-of-a-workflow-run.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/201-code-snippets-change-the-name-of-a-workflow-run.html</guid>
      <description>In some use cases you may want to customize the name of the workflow run/execution to suit your needs. For example it may be more practical to browse the workflow runs with having the name of the object the operation ran on such as &#34;Deploy vApp tcWebServer&#34; instead of the default &#34;Deploy vApp&#34;. It can also be usefull if you use the workflow run as a way to identify a particular one from an external application having an ID for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to provide vCenter Orchestrator customized workflows to your customers ?</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/197-how-to-provide-vcenter-orchestrator-customized-workflows-to-your-customers.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/197-how-to-provide-vcenter-orchestrator-customized-workflows-to-your-customers.html</guid>
      <description>Providing customized workflows to an internal or an external customer is a process following a typical software development lifecycle with specific orchestration requirements and best practices for setting up the environments and managing the content lifecycle.
1.1&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Workflow Development life cycleThis section summarizes briefly the different steps to observe to deliver custom workflows (or any custom application).
1.1.1&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Requirement gatheringGathering requirement consists of interviewing the customer on project characteristics such as planning, budget, scope, prioritization and constraints but also particular specific technical requirements such as:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring the vCenter Orchestrator Java Virtual Machine</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/196-monitoring-the-vcenter-orchestrator-java-virtual-machine.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/196-monitoring-the-vcenter-orchestrator-java-virtual-machine.html</guid>
      <description>Ever wondered how your vCenter Orchestrator is doing on memory usage ? vCenter Orchestrator Java Virtual Machine allocates a default of 2 GB Heap space.
It will consume more heap space as processes are running and will ultimately call the garbage collector to keep in memory only the used items.
If you are running a lot of workflows on your server or if you are experimenting custom workflows and plug-ins you may want to know how much of this memory is consumed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take cloud automation scripting to another level with cloud orchestration</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/172-take-cloud-automation-scripting-to-another-level-with-cloud-orchestration.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/172-take-cloud-automation-scripting-to-another-level-with-cloud-orchestration.html</guid>
      <description>I am always asked why choose orchestration over scripting. The short answer is that orchestration has a lot more to offer; the long answer is below.
I started to work in IT in 1995 after getting my analyst-programmer degree. Naturally I used scripted automation right away and never stopped since then. I have used batch, shell, vbscript, kix, perl and various other scripting languages to automate desktop and server automated provisioning and operations in physical and then virtual environments in the early 2000s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure the AMQP plug-in to monitor vCloud Director</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/179-configure-the-amqp-plug-in.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/179-configure-the-amqp-plug-in.html</guid>
      <description>OK, so we told you about the great new plug-in that VMware has made available for vCO to work with AMQP, but now what? You&#39;ll need a couple things to get started before you can run off and code a bunch of cool workflows so let&#39;s step through this initial process...
Get and Install AMQP Server (RabbitMQ)Configure Publisher (vCloud Director 1.5)Configure Consumer (vCenter Orchestrator)Apply Policy Template to create new PolicyHow to create new Policy manuallyStarting the PolicyGet and install an AMQP server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extend vCloud Director with vCenter Orchestrator</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/180-extend-vcloud-director-with-vcenter-orchestrator.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/180-extend-vcloud-director-with-vcenter-orchestrator.html</guid>
      <description>In a previous article we demonstrated how vCenter Orchestrator can leverage the vCloud Director plug-in to automate tasks or create new functionality by combining them. These workflows are initiated by vCenter Orchestrator.
Now if you would like to have vCO triggering workflows based on vCloud Director events (For example an end user task started from the vCloud Director UI, a system event or a task started from the vCloud API) you will be able to leverage the vCloud Director 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips: Export and import input parameters</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/182-tips-export-and-import-input-parameters.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/182-tips-export-and-import-input-parameters.html</guid>
      <description>VMware vCenter Orchestrator (vCO) keeps your last workflows inputs as long as you keep your vCO client open. It is very practical since it avoids filling all the input fields on each subsequent run of the same workflow.
Now if you close your client you have to refill these inputs except if ...
You use the following tip:
When your input are filled. Hold Alt and right click, A contextual menu appear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work with vCO over SSL</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/181-work-with-vco-over-ssl.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/181-work-with-vco-over-ssl.html</guid>
      <description>With the increasing popularity of VMware vCenter Orchestrator, there is a growing desire to use it over SSL connections. While vCO supports this type of connectivity out of the box, it is not necessarily pre-configured automatically to have a proper SSL certificate. Regardless of how or where you import the default certificate, you are unlikely to get away from warnings such as:
Firefox Warning: Internet Explorer Warning:
After clicking &#34;Continue to this website (not recommended).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Retrieve Workflow Execution Details</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/176-how-to-retrieve-workflow-execution-details.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/176-how-to-retrieve-workflow-execution-details.html</guid>
      <description>A common task among vCenter Orchestrator (vCO) developers is to check the results of workflows that have already executed. This can be done in the vCO Client by clicking the plus sign next to the Workflow you are checking on, but this isn&#39;t always the most desirable method. For instance, you may have a vCO Policy/Task setup to check the executions of other workflows at a recurring interval. The following code can help guide you to gathering the desired information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate VMware LabManager with vCenter Orchestrator</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/168-how-to-automate-labmanager-with-vco.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/168-how-to-automate-labmanager-with-vco.html</guid>
      <description>With the new released SOAP/REST plug-in you can automate everything you ever dreamed of! One of my favorite use cases is to automate the VMware Lab Manager operations with the SOAP plug-in. As many of you know the Lab Manager offers 2 APIs: an external and an internal one. The following examples are based on the internal API (https://YourLabManagerServer/LabManager/SOAP/LabmanagerInternal.asmx). This use case shows how to establish the VMware LabManager SOAP connection, create an new configuration, adding a template-based VM to the configuration, deploy the configuration and change the owner of the configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code snippets : Get VMs that triggered vCenter Alarms</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/169-code-snippets-get-vms-that-triggered-vcenter-alarms.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/169-code-snippets-get-vms-that-triggered-vcenter-alarms.html</guid>
      <description>If you ever wanted to start a workflow based on a VM triggering an alarm in vCenter the solution is a few click away.
The following action get all VMs that triggered alarms from any vCenter vCO is managing with filtering on Alarms names, acknowledged state, start time, status (warning, alert).
First go to the action tab. Right click on the root to create a new action module. Use the naming convention org.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial: Create your own Twitter Application with a vCO workflow in a few minutes</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/158-tutorial-create-your-own-twitter-application-with-a-vco-workflow-in-a-few-minutes.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/158-tutorial-create-your-own-twitter-application-with-a-vco-workflow-in-a-few-minutes.html</guid>
      <description>If you thought vCO was powerful, think again. The new SOAP and REST plug-in are taking it to new levels. With the following tutorial you can in as little as 30 minutes and without a single line of code (yes really !) create a workflow that will update your Twitter status. If you never had a chance to do a vCO Tutorial this one is really an easy one for starting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Force a VM to boot from several devices</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/164-force-a-vm-to-boot-from-several-devices.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/164-force-a-vm-to-boot-from-several-devices.html</guid>
      <description>One thing vCO users and administrators always ask for is changing the boot order for virtual machines. The bad news is: It is part of the BIOS of the virtual machine (.nvram). But based on this community discussion and the solutions in PowerShell, I decided to test it with the vCenter Orchestrator and I was surprised how easy it is!
1 2 3 4 5 6 7  var changedValue = new Array(); changedValue[0] = new VcOptionValue(); changedValue[0].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic delivery of customized VMs into vCloud Director</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/163-automatic-delivery-of-customized-vms-into-vcloud-director.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/163-automatic-delivery-of-customized-vms-into-vcloud-director.html</guid>
      <description>One of our colleagues, Christian Johannsen has posted a new article on the VMware vCenter Orchestrator blog onhow to automatically create a customized VM in Virtual Center and import it in vCloud director.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Blog demonstrates an user accounts creation scenario with the Active Directory Plug-in for vCenter Orchestrator</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/159-vmware-blog-demonstrates-an-user-accounts-creation-scenario-with-the-active-directory-plug-in-for-vcenter-orchestrator.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/159-vmware-blog-demonstrates-an-user-accounts-creation-scenario-with-the-active-directory-plug-in-for-vcenter-orchestrator.html</guid>
      <description>Following the release of the Microsoft Active Directory plug-in VMware demonstrates how to combine building block workflows into a custom one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vCloud Director vApp hot clone in less than one hour Solution Video</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/147-vcloud-director-vapp-hot-clone-in-less-than-one-hour-solution-video.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/147-vcloud-director-vapp-hot-clone-in-less-than-one-hour-solution-video.html</guid>
      <description>Did you have trouble getting things &#34;just right&#34; in our previous tutorial &#34;Create your own vCloud Director vApp hot clone in less than one hour&#34;? No worries, we&#39;ve just added our solution video to YouTube!!  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Need an analogy around vCO and vCloud Director?</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/145-need-an-analogy-around-vco-and-vcloud-director.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/145-need-an-analogy-around-vco-and-vcloud-director.html</guid>
      <description>We recently came across a nice little analogy around vCloud Director (vCD) and vCenter Orchestrator (vCO) from one of the folks over at NetApp on their blog. The article &#34;What is vCloud Director, really?&#34; cleverly equates vCD to the manager of an apartment complex and vCO to the maintenance man who does work for the manager and other managers (products). Please take a moment to learn more about vCO through this analogy and see what NetApp has to offer with their plugin for vCO!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial: Create your own vCloud Director vApp hot clone in less than one hour</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/140-vcloud-director-vapp-hot-clone.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/140-vcloud-director-vapp-hot-clone.html</guid>
      <description>This article is the first tutorial covering a practical use of the recently released VMware vCloud Director plug-in. It is meant to be educational rather than exhaustive.
A while ago I wanted to make a copy of a running vCloud director vApp. When you use the vCloud Director user interface as an Organization Administrator you have the following options:
Copy operations are grayed out.
While there is certainly a very good reason for not supporting copy of running vApps I wanted to explore this further with leveraging the vCloud API through the vCenter Orchestrator plug-in for vCD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vCenter Orchestrator identify permission problems</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/138-vcenter-orchestrator-identify-permission-problems.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/138-vcenter-orchestrator-identify-permission-problems.html</guid>
      <description>These days I had a strange scenario in a large customer environment. Every time I tried to start a workflow via SOAP from a webservice client there was an error. After regarding this in the vCO client I found out that every run from the external webservice client causes the action &#34;getAllVMs&#34; to fail. Disconcertingly the array &#34;VMs&#34; wasnt filled by the action and there was no error message.The error occurs later in the workflow because of the empty array.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware KB TV - How to install and configure VMware vCenter Orchestrator Plug-in for vCloud Director</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/133-vmware-kb-tv-how-to-install-and-configure-vmware-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in-for-vcloud-director.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/133-vmware-kb-tv-how-to-install-and-configure-vmware-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in-for-vcloud-director.html</guid>
      <description>We are proud to announce that vCO Team members and VMware KB TV have released the &#34;How to install and configure VMware vCenter Orchestrator Plug-in for vCloud Director&#34; video. This video is published on the excellent VMware KB blog and the VMwareKB channel on youtube. We definitely recommend you to subscribe to these and to follow VMware KB on twitter.
Thousands of visitors have consulted our installation and configuration articles in the last few months and these are the only articles getting more and more traffic week after week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mightycare vCenter Orchestrator code snippets</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/125-mightycare-vco-code-snippets.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/125-mightycare-vco-code-snippets.html</guid>
      <description>vCO Team is delighted to see vCenter Orchestrator knowledge being spread around the world. One of the VMware partners, Mightycare has a few vCO specialists who not only do a great job delivering automation and orchestration to VMware customers but also share their knowledge online. Here is a collection of the last code snippets they have published.
 Use and examples of RegExp (regular expression)Get all Distributed Virtual Switches vCOUnzip Files with VMware Orchestrator workflow vCOAccess to Java ClassesSOAP connect via VB .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vCenter Orchestrator VCAP Topic Brown Bag</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/124-vcenter-orchestrator-vcap-topic-brown-bag.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/124-vcenter-orchestrator-vcap-topic-brown-bag.html</guid>
      <description>Our friend @cody_bunch at ProfessionalVMware.com hosts an online VCAP Study session every other week. These &#34;Brown Bag&#34; sessions provide expert guidance and feedback on the night&#39;s topic. Our very own Burke Azbill recently participated on the panel for the vCenter Orchestrator Brown Bag session. If you happened to miss the session, don&#39;t worry - it was recorded and may be viewed here: VCAP-DCA BrownBag - Section 8 Orchestrator Follow-Up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code snippets : Cancel one of your running workflows</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/123-code-snippets-cancel-one-of-your-running-workflows.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/123-code-snippets-cancel-one-of-your-running-workflows.html</guid>
      <description>It has been a while without publishing a tutorial. With the growing activities around vCO the vCO team members have been very busy and doing such tutorials takes a lot of time. Since a lot of you already went through the basics we can now give you some code snippets that you can use in your own workflows. Here is the first one. I will eventually improve the article if people ask for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some tips for new vCO plug-in developers (II)</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/115-some-tips-for-new-vco-plug-in-developers-ii.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/115-some-tips-for-new-vco-plug-in-developers-ii.html</guid>
      <description>This is the 2nd part of the previous post Some tips for new vCO plug-in developers (I). These tips are more focused on the workflows than on the plug-in project itself.
Again I&#39;ve grouped them by type.
Workflows &amp;amp; Actions
Start developing workflows as building blocksA building block would be a simple workflow that requires some few input parameters and returns some simple output. If we have a rich (and good) set of building blocks it will be much easier to create higher-level workflows and we will offer the users a better set of tools to compose their own complex workflows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some tips for new vCO plug-in developers (I)</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/114-some-tips-for-new-vco-plug-in-developers-i.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/114-some-tips-for-new-vco-plug-in-developers-i.html</guid>
      <description>Here is a small list of tips for those ones who start with the vCO plug-in development. Some of the tips are just some kind of advice that will help you to keep the things clear. Others may make you think about future and possible problems and how to face them up. And finally some other tips will be useful &#34;just&#34; to avoid simple (~ easy-to-fix) problems usually reported by the QA engineers before the final users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expand your vCO library with Onyx</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/113-expand-your-vco-library-with-onyx.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/113-expand-your-vco-library-with-onyx.html</guid>
      <description>vCO is shipped with a large library of actions and workflows for the most common vCenter operations. However since vCenter is extremely rich in terms of features and you may have been in the situation where there is no action or workflow for a given vCenter Operation. Thanks to vCO vCenter plug-in exposing the entire vCenter API as javascript objects and methods you can always explore its API documentation and craft your own actions and workflows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware KB TV - How to install and configure VMware vCenter Orchestrator</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/109-vmware-kb-tv-how-to-install-vmware-vcenter-orchestrator.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/109-vmware-kb-tv-how-to-install-vmware-vcenter-orchestrator.html</guid>
      <description>We are proud to announce that vCO Team members and VMware KB TV today released vCO 4.1 installation and configuration videos. These videos were published on the excellent VMware KB blog and VMwareKB channel on youtube. We definitely recommend you to subscribe to these and to follow VMware KB on twitter.
Thousands of visitors have consulted our installation and configuration articles in the last few months and these are the only articles getting more and more traffic week after week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a Simple vCO Self Service VM Provisioning Portal - Part 3</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/107-create-a-simple-vco-self-service-vm-provisioning-portal-part-3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/107-create-a-simple-vco-self-service-vm-provisioning-portal-part-3.html</guid>
      <description>In part two of this series, you learned how to use a user interaction workflow element to allow for an approver to approve a server request. You also learned that a number of permissions are required throughout vCO in order for the approval to actually perform the server request. It is likely that you would have to modify permissions on several other workflows and actions throughout vCO in order for tutorial 2 to fully work for a non-admin account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating workflow loops</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/102-creating-workflow-loops.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/102-creating-workflow-loops.html</guid>
      <description>VMware&#39;s vCenter Orchestrator (vCO) ships with a rich library of workflows and actions. The workflows are often designed to handle a single object instance such as a VM. Technical workflows frequently require selecting several VMs by VM folder, resource pool, or by one of their properties (power state, Operating System, Hardware version ...).
Some of our readers have asked how to deal with selecting VMs for a mass operation workflow. This article should cover the basis required to do so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lifecycle Manager Reports made Excel Friendly</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/101-lifecycle-manager-reports-made-excel-friendly.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/101-lifecycle-manager-reports-made-excel-friendly.html</guid>
      <description>Have you ever tried opening a VMware Lifecycle Manager (LCM) report.xml file with Excel? Probably didn&#39;t have much luck, right? The following brief tutorial will walk you through the steps necessary to make these reports generate XML files that can be opened by Excel (Disclaimer: I did my tests with Excel 2007.) Please click the Read More link to see the rest of this article.
Finding the Report Workflows and Editing themTo get started, you will need to launch your vCenter Orchestrator Client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create an all in one vCO dev server on Windows 2008 64-bit</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/96-how-to-create-an-all-in-one-vco-dev-server-on-windows-2008-64-bit.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/96-how-to-create-an-all-in-one-vco-dev-server-on-windows-2008-64-bit.html</guid>
      <description>The recently released vCenter Orchestrator 4.1 requires and takes advantage of a 64-bit OS. For development purposes, it can be desirable to have a single server to perform the following roles:
Windows Domain Controller (Active Directory)E-mail Server (POP3/SMTP)Database ServervCenter ServervCO ServervCO ClientThis short article is intended to help you get all these services running on a single server. Setting up these features in an incorrect order may result in conflicting ports and/or the inability to get some of the software installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Configure vCenter Orchestrator (vCO)</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/89-how-to-configure-vcenter-orchestrator-vco.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/89-how-to-configure-vcenter-orchestrator-vco.html</guid>
      <description>In my previous article How to install vCenter Orchestrator (vCO), I walked you through a screen-by-screen installation of vCO. The only major item lacking from that previous article is the ever-important configuration steps. In the past, many people have had troubles with getting the configuration of vCO correct. This article is an effort to help walk you through each of the screens to provide you insight and recommendations on how to get vCenter Orchestrator configured and working in your environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a simple vCO self service VM Provisioning Portal - Part 2</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/87-create-a-simple-vco-self-service-vm-provisioning-portal-part-2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/87-create-a-simple-vco-self-service-vm-provisioning-portal-part-2.html</guid>
      <description>This second tutorial assumes you have completed part 1 and use the Provision VM workflow.
Concepts covered in this article include:
How to create a Workflow using subworkflowsHow to map inputs, outputs, and attributesHow to use user interactionsHow to do basic presentationsHow to use validation presentation propertiesHow to handle exception and write to the event logHow to use vCO Server and System objects in scriptable boxesHow to use the API searchHow to launch a Workflow from the vCenter Orchestrator ClientHow to launch a Workflow from a webview, using the vCenter Orchestrator WeboperatorHow to set rights on workflowsHow to set up the vCO mail plug-inNOTE: Webviews were deprecated and removed in vRealize Orchestrator 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a simple vCO self service VM Provisioning Portal - Part 1</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/54-create-a-simple-vco-self-service-vm-provisioning-portal-part-1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/54-create-a-simple-vco-self-service-vm-provisioning-portal-part-1.html</guid>
      <description>This article is the first in a series of tutorials for developing a basic VM self service portal. It is meant to be educational rather than exhaustive. Other articles will follow up for supporting more advanced features and a less static configuration.
Concepts covered in this article include:
How to create a simple WorkflowHow to map inputs, outputs, and attributesHow to launch a Workflow from a webview, using the vCenter Orchestrator WeboperatorHow to launch a Workflow from the vCenter Orchestrator ClientNOTE: Webviews were deprecated and removed in vRealize Orchestrator 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install vCenter Orchestrator (vCO)</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/47-how-to-install-vcenter-orchestrator-vco.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/47-how-to-install-vcenter-orchestrator-vco.html</guid>
      <description>This article will describe the steps necessary to install and configure VMware vCenter Orchestrator (VCO). Parts of the configuration are often a challenge even for experienced administrators. My goal here is to help you get a functional VCO server up and running.
I&#39;ve even put together a step-by-step video on How to Install vCenter Orchestrator here on vCOTeam.info ! Take a look &amp;amp; tell your colleagues!
Updated comments for vCO 4.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
