<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Twitter on vCO Team</title>
    <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/tags/twitter.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Twitter on vCO Team</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.vcoteam.info/tags/twitter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Types tutorial : Implement your own Twitter plug-in without any scripting</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/282-dynamic-types-tutorial-implement-your-own-twitter-plug-in-without-any-scripting.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/282-dynamic-types-tutorial-implement-your-own-twitter-plug-in-without-any-scripting.html</guid>
      <description>In a previous article I have explained how the vCO dynamic Types allow to simplify the development of vCO plug-ins and how these are leveraged by VMware vCloud Automation Center XaaS. It is now time to experiment with creating a plugin with leveraging the Dynamic Types plug-in generator package.
Warning: You can do it without Java development experience and without having to write a single line of scripting !
As a first step download the Dynamic Types plug-in generator package from VMware communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial: Create your own Twitter Application with a vCO workflow in a few minutes</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/158-tutorial-create-your-own-twitter-application-with-a-vco-workflow-in-a-few-minutes.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/158-tutorial-create-your-own-twitter-application-with-a-vco-workflow-in-a-few-minutes.html</guid>
      <description>If you thought vCO was powerful, think again. The new SOAP and REST plug-in are taking it to new levels. With the following tutorial you can in as little as 30 minutes and without a single line of code (yes really !) create a workflow that will update your Twitter status. If you never had a chance to do a vCO Tutorial this one is really an easy one for starting.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>