<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>vRA on vCO Team</title>
    <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/tags/vra.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in vRA on vCO Team</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.vcoteam.info/tags/vra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building a Kubernetes Blueprint for vRealize Automation - Intro</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/326-building-a-kubernetes-blueprint-for-vra-intro.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/326-building-a-kubernetes-blueprint-for-vra-intro.html</guid>
      <description>In my efforts to learn more in the Cloud Native Apps space, I recently attended DockerCon 2018 and have been playing around with Docker a bit so I get the basics. Since VMware has Pivotal Container Services (PKS) for self-hosted enterprise ready Kubernetes and VMware Kubernetes Engine (VKE) as an upcoming SaaS offering, I figured it was time to start getting a feel for Kubernetes.
Docker Training For the first two days of DockerCon, I opted for the Docker Fundamentals training as an add-on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Configure vRA&#39;s Embedded vRO to Allow Domain Account Login</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/312-how-to-configure-vra-s-embedded-vro-to-allow-domain-account-login.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/312-how-to-configure-vra-s-embedded-vro-to-allow-domain-account-login.html</guid>
      <description>Two years ago, I wrote a similar article around vCAC&amp;rsquo;s embedded vCO but a lot has changed since then so those older steps no longer apply. This brief article will quickly walk you through the steps required to allow vRealize Automation 7.0/7.1/7.2&amp;rsquo;s embedded vRealize Orchestrator to allow Active Directory Domain accounts login to the vRO Client.
Pre-Requisites This article assumes the following:
 vRealize Automation 7.0-7.2 is installed and configured (NOTE: This has not been tested with 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a plug-in for a REST based web service in minutes - part 1</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/298-create-a-plug-in-for-a-rest-web-service-in-minutes.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/298-create-a-plug-in-for-a-rest-web-service-in-minutes.html</guid>
      <description>In a previous article I have explained how Dynamic Types work and how these are very useful to create a vCO / vRO plugin that will enable the XaaS capabilitites of vCAC / vRA.
Then explained how to build your own twitter plug-in using the plug-in generator package. I have now extended the capabilities of the plug-in generator and will attempt to demonstrate these in this new series of articles. This article use NSX as the orchestrated endpoint but following the explanation included on this tutorial you should be able to get it to work with many REST web service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Plug-in &#43; DynamicTypes = Simple CMDB for vCAC - Part 3</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/294-sql-plug-in-dynamictypes-simple-cmdb-for-vcac-part-3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/294-sql-plug-in-dynamictypes-simple-cmdb-for-vcac-part-3.html</guid>
      <description>Welcome back! This is the third article of a multi-part series that steps you through the process of exposing our workflows from the last article to vRealize Automation&amp;rsquo;s (vRA) Advanced Service Designer (ASD).
Introduction This third article will cover the following topics:
 How to add the simple CMDB to vRealize Automation&amp;rsquo;s Advanced Service Designer Add a Day 2 operation to delete an Asset from our table  Future article will cover the following topic:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Plug-in &#43; DynamicTypes = Simple CMDB for vCAC - Part 2</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/292-sql-plug-in-dynamictypes-simple-cmdb-for-vcac-part-2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/292-sql-plug-in-dynamictypes-simple-cmdb-for-vcac-part-2.html</guid>
      <description>Welcome back! This is the second article of a multi-part series that steps you through the process of mapping a SQL table into vRealize Orchestrator, building out a DynamicTypes plug-in inventory based on that table, then exposing it to vRealize Automation&amp;rsquo;s Advanced Service Designer (ASD). In the first article, we got our database table mapped using the SQL Plug-in and generated some CRUD workflows.
Introduction Let&amp;rsquo;s build a simple Dynamic Types plug-in around our SQL Table that we created in our previous article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Plug-in &#43; DynamicTypes = Simple CMDB for vCAC - Part 1</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/291-sql-plug-in-dynamictypes-simple-cmdb-for-vcac-part-1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/291-sql-plug-in-dynamictypes-simple-cmdb-for-vcac-part-1.html</guid>
      <description>This multi-part series will step you through the process of mapping a Microsoft SQL Server table into vRealize Orchestrator, building out a DynamicTypes plug-in inventory based on that table (using my workflow package), then exposing it to vRealize Automation&amp;rsquo;s Advanced Service Designer (ASD).
Introduction vRealize Automation (vRA) features an Advanced Service Designer (ASD) that allows for you to offer nearly anything as a service (XaaS). In order to take advantage of that feature, it requires a vRealize Orchestrator (vRO) Inventory object.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
