<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SQL on vCO Team</title>
    <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/tags/sql.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in SQL on vCO Team</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.vcoteam.info/tags/sql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Plug-in &#43; DynamicTypes = Simple CMDB for vCAC - Part 3</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/294-sql-plug-in-dynamictypes-simple-cmdb-for-vcac-part-3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/294-sql-plug-in-dynamictypes-simple-cmdb-for-vcac-part-3.html</guid>
      <description>Welcome back! This is the third article of a multi-part series that steps you through the process of exposing our workflows from the last article to vRealize Automation&amp;rsquo;s (vRA) Advanced Service Designer (ASD).
Introduction This third article will cover the following topics:
 How to add the simple CMDB to vRealize Automation&amp;rsquo;s Advanced Service Designer Add a Day 2 operation to delete an Asset from our table  Future article will cover the following topic:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Plug-in &#43; DynamicTypes = Simple CMDB for vCAC - Part 2</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/292-sql-plug-in-dynamictypes-simple-cmdb-for-vcac-part-2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/292-sql-plug-in-dynamictypes-simple-cmdb-for-vcac-part-2.html</guid>
      <description>Welcome back! This is the second article of a multi-part series that steps you through the process of mapping a SQL table into vRealize Orchestrator, building out a DynamicTypes plug-in inventory based on that table, then exposing it to vRealize Automation&amp;rsquo;s Advanced Service Designer (ASD). In the first article, we got our database table mapped using the SQL Plug-in and generated some CRUD workflows.
Introduction Let&amp;rsquo;s build a simple Dynamic Types plug-in around our SQL Table that we created in our previous article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Plug-in &#43; DynamicTypes = Simple CMDB for vCAC - Part 1</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/291-sql-plug-in-dynamictypes-simple-cmdb-for-vcac-part-1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/291-sql-plug-in-dynamictypes-simple-cmdb-for-vcac-part-1.html</guid>
      <description>This multi-part series will step you through the process of mapping a Microsoft SQL Server table into vRealize Orchestrator, building out a DynamicTypes plug-in inventory based on that table (using my workflow package), then exposing it to vRealize Automation&amp;rsquo;s Advanced Service Designer (ASD).
Introduction vRealize Automation (vRA) features an Advanced Service Designer (ASD) that allows for you to offer nearly anything as a service (XaaS). In order to take advantage of that feature, it requires a vRealize Orchestrator (vRO) Inventory object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware released the vCenter Orchestrator SQL Plug-in</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/223-vmware-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-sql-plug-in.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/223-vmware-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-sql-plug-in.html</guid>
      <description>If you ever wanted to integrate your workflows with a database with having your database records available as part of the inventory then this plug-in will help you to do so.
Chances are that at some point you will need to read or write information from an SQL database as part of your workflows. vCenter Orchestrator provides some scripter / developper capabilities such as the JDBC plug-in and the integration with the hybernate framework.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>