<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on vCO Team</title>
    <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on vCO Team</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 15:54:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An Honest review of the TTS Service Synthesys</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/synthesis.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/synthesis.html</guid>
      <description>I use Text To Speech (TTS) pretty regularly on MacOS to read content to me with a simply key combination. Up until recently, that was the extent of my interest or need in it.
My wife was interested in creating short english lesson videos in a cartoon format, but neither of us wanted to act out the character voices. Enter TTS. This took place in the beginning of September so we started looking around for a nice Text To Speech solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Kubernetes Blueprint for vRealize Automation - Intro</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/326-building-a-kubernetes-blueprint-for-vra-intro.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/326-building-a-kubernetes-blueprint-for-vra-intro.html</guid>
      <description>In my efforts to learn more in the Cloud Native Apps space, I recently attended DockerCon 2018 and have been playing around with Docker a bit so I get the basics. Since VMware has Pivotal Container Services (PKS) for self-hosted enterprise ready Kubernetes and VMware Kubernetes Engine (VKE) as an upcoming SaaS offering, I figured it was time to start getting a feel for Kubernetes.
Docker Training For the first two days of DockerCon, I opted for the Docker Fundamentals training as an add-on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
