<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Plug-in on vCO Team</title>
    <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/tags/plug-in.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Plug-in on vCO Team</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.vcoteam.info/tags/plug-in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create a Microsoft DNS Dynamic Types plug-in ?</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/323-how-to-create-a-microsoft-dns-dynamic-types-plug-in.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/323-how-to-create-a-microsoft-dns-dynamic-types-plug-in.html</guid>
      <description>On the VMware blog I have explained how vRealize Automation Anything as a Service (XaaS) work with Orchestrator and how a vRO plug-in works.
In this tutorial I will walk you through how I managed to implement Microsoft DNS as a service I used for the screenshot examples on that blog including:
 The Microsoft DNS dynamic types plug-in DNS record as a service in vRA DNS record as a blueprint component  This is the first public tutorial on how to create a Dynamic Types plug-in from scratch and the overall methodology used applies to other integrations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plug-in Generator v2 advanced techniques</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/302-create-a-plug-in-for-orchestrator.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/302-create-a-plug-in-for-orchestrator.html</guid>
      <description>In previous tutorials we created inventory object types, their children objects, workflows to operate these that we packaged for our end users.
In this tutorial we are going to create an orchestrator plug-in to list vCO / vRO workflows ! You may wonder why doing so ?
This is a good use case for leveraging some of the more advanced features of the plug-in generator v2 to handle complex REST APIs and improving performance when needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a plug-in for a REST based web service in minutes - part 1</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/298-create-a-plug-in-for-a-rest-web-service-in-minutes.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/298-create-a-plug-in-for-a-rest-web-service-in-minutes.html</guid>
      <description>In a previous article I have explained how Dynamic Types work and how these are very useful to create a vCO / vRO plugin that will enable the XaaS capabilitites of vCAC / vRA.
Then explained how to build your own twitter plug-in using the plug-in generator package. I have now extended the capabilities of the plug-in generator and will attempt to demonstrate these in this new series of articles. This article use NSX as the orchestrated endpoint but following the explanation included on this tutorial you should be able to get it to work with many REST web service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Horizon vCenter Orchestrator Plug-in Released</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/288-vmware-horizon-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in-released.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/288-vmware-horizon-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in-released.html</guid>
      <description>Hello all you end user compute admins! If you&#39;ve been waiting for a vCO plug-in for your Horizon environment, your wait is over. Join Aaron Black in this &#34;Getting Started with vCenter Orchestrator Horizon Plug In&#34; video.  In order to get the plug-in, you must be licensed for Horizon 6.0 Enterprise. For a quick link to the download (login required at VMware&#39;s site), click Links -&amp;gt; Plug Ins, then scroll down to the &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware released new and updated vCO plug-ins</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/283-vmware-released-new-and-updated-vco-plug-ins.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/283-vmware-released-new-and-updated-vco-plug-ins.html</guid>
      <description>vCO has again been extended with a new plug-in an updates of existing plug-ins.
VMware vCenter Orchestrator AWS 1.0 Plug-in (New)VMware vCenter Orchestrator Auto-Deploy 5.5.1 Plug-in (Updated)VMware vCenter Orchestrator Multi-Node 5.5.1 Plug-in (Updated)VMware vCenter Orchestrator AMQP 1.0.3 Plug-in (Updated)VMware vCenter Orchestrator PowerShell 1.0.4 Plug-in (Updated)VMware vCloud Automation Center 6.0.1 Plug-in (Updated) - released date April 25, 2014 (article updated to include this entry)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Types tutorial : Implement your own Twitter plug-in without any scripting</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/282-dynamic-types-tutorial-implement-your-own-twitter-plug-in-without-any-scripting.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/282-dynamic-types-tutorial-implement-your-own-twitter-plug-in-without-any-scripting.html</guid>
      <description>In a previous article I have explained how the vCO dynamic Types allow to simplify the development of vCO plug-ins and how these are leveraged by VMware vCloud Automation Center XaaS. It is now time to experiment with creating a plugin with leveraging the Dynamic Types plug-in generator package.
Warning: You can do it without Java development experience and without having to write a single line of scripting !
As a first step download the Dynamic Types plug-in generator package from VMware communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use the SOAPInterceptor to see the SOAP Header and Body</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/267-how-to-use-the-soapinterceptor-to-see-the-soap-header-and-body.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/267-how-to-use-the-soapinterceptor-to-see-the-soap-header-and-body.html</guid>
      <description>On a recent project, I was having trouble figuring out why invoking a SOAP operation kept failing with the vCO SOAP plug-in. The inputs I was providing appeared to be correct and worked just fine with soapUI. This short tutorial will teach you how to use the SOAPInterceptor to display the Header and Body that the SOAP plug-in is sending.
SOAP Operation Auto-Generated Workflow   A typical Invoke Operation workflow looks similar to the above image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Several vCenter Orchestrator plug-ins updates</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/242-several-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-ins-updates.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/242-several-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-ins-updates.html</guid>
      <description>It has just been announced on the VMware Orchestrator communities, several plug-ins have been updated with some critical updates, some new requested features and some minor fixes.
Quoting the communities post:
 vCO-Powershell-Plug-in -1.0.1 - kerberos support added vCO-SQL-Plug-in -1.1.0 - two related plugins combined with auto-generation as well as advanced SQL scripts. A few important issues fixed.  vCO-vCenter-Plug-in - 5.0.1.1 - Critical update. Fixes a major issue with performance and losing attributes value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware released the vCenter Orchestrator Plug-in for vShield 5.0</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/241-vmware-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in-for-vshield-50.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/241-vmware-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in-for-vshield-50.html</guid>
      <description>Quoting the release notes:
The VMware vCenter Orchestrator plug-in for vShield allows vShield administrators to simplify the management of their vShield infrastructure by extending the robust workflow automation platform of VMware to the vShield environment. These workflows are built using the drag-and-drop capability of the workflow editor in the Orchestrator client. vCenter Orchestrator uses the plug-in to access the functionality of vShield and the vShield APIs. The included, pre-built workflows simplify the process to get you started with custom workflow creation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware released the vCenter Orchestrator Plug-in for VMware vCenter Chargeback Manager 2.0</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/233-vmware-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in-for-vmware-vcenter-chargeback-manager-20.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/233-vmware-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in-for-vmware-vcenter-chargeback-manager-20.html</guid>
      <description>Another new VMware plug-in release for vCenter Orchestrator, this time for vCenter Chargeback Manager.
You can use the plug-in to run Orchestrator workflows that automate vCenter Chargeback processes. In this release, the plug-in contains sample workflows.
You can also create custom workflows that implement the plug-in API to automate tasks in your vCenter Chargeback Manager environment.
The vCenter Chargeback Manager plug-in API provides various Javascript objects such as cost models, fixed costs, and hierarchies, that are created in you vCenter Chargeback Manager instance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware released the vCenter Orchestrator Multi-Node Plug-in</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/221-vmware-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-multi-node-plug-in.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/221-vmware-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-multi-node-plug-in.html</guid>
      <description>If you are designing enterprise wide Orchestration you may need to consider more than a single instance of vCenter Orchestrator. The vCenter Orchestrator Multi-Node Plug-in can help you doing so with offering the ability of a vCenter Orchestrator server to remote control other vCenter Orchestrator servers.
What this plug-in provides is:
Publish the remote vCenter Orchestrator library elements (Configurations, Packgaesm Workflows, Actions and Resources) in the master vCenter Orchestrator inventoryPublish the remote vCenter Orchestrator inventory elements (vCenter, vCloud Director, Microsoft AD, Cisco UCS, .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware released the vCenter Orchestrator Plug-in for Microsoft Windows PowerShell</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/220-vmware-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in-for-microsoft-windows-powershell.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/220-vmware-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in-for-microsoft-windows-powershell.html</guid>
      <description>If you have an investment in PowerShell cmdlets such as VMware vSphere PowerCLI but also snapins from other vendors the VMware vCenter Orchestrator plug-in for Microsoft Windows PowerShell can help you to integrate these as part of workflows steps in vCenter Orchestrator.
Citing the release notes:
The plug-in offers many capabilities to workflow developers, such as:

Invoking unmodified scripts by copying and pasting them into workflowsInvoking external scripts and passing workflow parameters as script inputsGenerating a new Orchestrator action from a PowerShell scriptGenerating a new Orchestrator action for a PowerCLI cmdletBrowsing snap-ins and their associated cmdlets in the Orchestrator workflow editorInvoking scripts from the Orchestrator JavaScript APIConverting vCenter Server objects in Orchestrator workflows to PowerShell objects and the reverseThe VMware vCenter Orchestrator plug-in for Microsoft Windows PowerShell 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware released the vCenter Orchestrator Plug-in for vSphere Auto Deploy</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/222-vmware-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in-for-vsphere-auto-deploy.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/222-vmware-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in-for-vsphere-auto-deploy.html</guid>
      <description>If you are booting your ESXi servers from the network using vSphere Auto Deploy then this plug-in allows you to automate tasks for configuring and provisioning stateless ESXi hosts.
The plug-in exposes an inventory and CRUD opratons for:
ESXi depotsHost profilesRule setsThere are workflows to manage answer files and to reprovision a host using answer files, host profiles, new image.
For more information check the VMware vCenter Orchestrator Plug-In for vSphere Auto Deployrelease notes, documentation and download</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware released the vCenter Orchestrator SQL Plug-in</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/223-vmware-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-sql-plug-in.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/223-vmware-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-sql-plug-in.html</guid>
      <description>If you ever wanted to integrate your workflows with a database with having your database records available as part of the inventory then this plug-in will help you to do so.
Chances are that at some point you will need to read or write information from an SQL database as part of your workflows. vCenter Orchestrator provides some scripter / developper capabilities such as the JDBC plug-in and the integration with the hybernate framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vCloud Director orchestrated infrastructure provisioning featuring VCE UIM vCO plug-in preview</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/219-vcloud-director-orchestrated-infrastructure-provisioning-featuring-vce-uim-vco-plug-in-preview.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/219-vcloud-director-orchestrated-infrastructure-provisioning-featuring-vce-uim-vco-plug-in-preview.html</guid>
      <description>VCE, the company formed by Cisco and EMC with investments from VMware and Intel is showing a demonstration of their vCenter Orchestrator powered infrastructure provisioning for vCloud Director. This is done with using EMC Unified Infrastructure Manager (UIM) which is the single pane of glass managing the stand alone Vblock Element Management applications.
If you followed the vCenter Orchestrator plug-in releases you must have noticed the UCS Manager release. So, how is a UIM plug-in different ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware released the vCenter Orchestrator Plug-in update for vCloud Director 1.5</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/213-vmware-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in-update-for-vcloud-director-15.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/213-vmware-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in-update-for-vcloud-director-15.html</guid>
      <description>I will re-iterate what I have said about nine months ago : Today VMware released the most complete automation solution for vCloud Director as a free download ! This is a plug-in for vCenter Orchestrator allowing to orchestrate vCloud Director 1.5 with a large collection of out of the box workflows. The previous version of this plug-in (1.02) is used at several service providers and enterprise customers.
As before in terms of functionality the plug-in allows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code snippets : Create your database plug-in</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/203-code-snippets-create-your-database-plug-in.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/203-code-snippets-create-your-database-plug-in.html</guid>
      <description>Need vCO to fetch some data from a database for integration purposes ? There is an easy solution with creating a plug-in ...
Jöerg Lew wrote an excellent article on the different options to integrate vCO with a database here. Creating a hibernate based plug-in is definitely the best way to map a database as vCO objects but it is a lot of effort and can get quite complex.
Since there is another much simpler way to create a database plug-in (with read only rights on the database) I thought I should share it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Labs released the vCenter Orchestrator CIM Plug-in</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/204-vmware-labs-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-cim-plug-in.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/204-vmware-labs-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-cim-plug-in.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;
Here is yet another vCenter Orchestrator (vCO) plug-in. This time to enable a set of discovery and monitoring features.
Citing the CIM plug-in summary page:
 
ESX includes a CIM Object Manager (CIMOM) that implements a set of server discovery and monitoring features. With the VMware CIM SMASH/Server Management API, clients that use industry-standard protocols can do the following:
 Enumerate system resourcesMonitor system health dataThe plugin is general enough to support other CIM compliant services and is not limited only to ESX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Labs released the Perspectives Plug-in</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/202-vmware-labs-released-the-perspectives-plug-in.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/202-vmware-labs-released-the-perspectives-plug-in.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;
You may wonder what &#34;Perspectives&#34; application this may be orchestrating. In fact this plug-in offers a simple way for the VI administrator to give the vCO users access to specific workflows through a web interface.
Citing the official documentation:
&#34;Perspectives is an Orchestrator Web view that allows a limited group of users to run or schedule certain tasks through a Web browser, without logging in to the Orchestrator client. vCenter administrators can use</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware published the vCenter Orchestrator Plug-ins Documentation Center</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/195-vmware-published-the-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-ins-documentation-center.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/195-vmware-published-the-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-ins-documentation-center.html</guid>
      <description>VMware released nine plug-ins for vCenter Orchestrator this year (and there is more than a quarter left !) and decided that it would be best for customers to have all of the docs gathered in one place in a more user friendly and searchable format.
vCenter Orchestrator Plug-ins Documentation Center allows from one single page to browse the different plug-ins documentation.

Also these documentation guides are also made available in .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware released an update for the vCenter Orchestrator for vCloud Director 1.01</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/194-vmware-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in-update-for-vcloud-director-101.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/194-vmware-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in-update-for-vcloud-director-101.html</guid>
      <description>VMware release a version 1.02 of the vCenter Orchestrator Plug-in for vCloud Director (1.0 or 1.01).
This is a maintenance release.
Quoting the release notes :
Version 1.0.2 of the vCloud Director plug-in improves the performance, addresses a number of issues, and includes the sample workflow package. To upgrade the plug-in, you must install version 1.0.2 on top of your existing installation.
It is recommended to update to this version since it corrects a problem happening when workflows waiting for a vCloud Director task are running concurrently and other issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infoblox released a Tech Note on their vCenter Orchestrator plug-in</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/193-infoblox-released-a-tech-note-on-their-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/193-infoblox-released-a-tech-note-on-their-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in.html</guid>
      <description>Following their press-release and VMworld 2011 presentation Infoblox has now published a technical note which can help you to learn how the Infoblox VMware vCenter Orchestrator Plug-in alleviates the challenges of IP Address Management within rapidly expanding virtualized environments.
Quoting a part of the Tech Note:
The plug-in was developed for and is delivered with the VMware vCenter Orchestrator (vCO), which works in tandem with the VMware vCloud Director (vCD). The vCD provides automated IP addressing and related management capabilities in real time as virtual machines are created and destroyed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware released the vCenter Orchestrator Plug-in for vCenter Server 5.0</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/190-vmware-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in-for-vcenter-server-50.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/190-vmware-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in-for-vcenter-server-50.html</guid>
      <description>vCenter Orchestrator 4.2 shipped with vCenter 5 including a vCenter 4.1 plug-in. While being usable with vCenter 5 it does not leverage the new functionality of vCenter 5. This has now being taken care of with the release of the vCenter 5 plug-in. Not only the plug-in exposes 100% of the vCenter 5 API it also provides a lot of additional workflows for networking and host configuration.
Some of these workflows include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware released the vCenter Orchestrator SNMP Plug-in</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/191-vmware-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-snmp-plug-in.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/191-vmware-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-snmp-plug-in.html</guid>
      <description>This SNMP plug-in allows vCenter Orchestrator to connect and receive information from Simple Network Management Protocol enabled systems.
In terms of capabilities the plug-ins allows to:
Register SNMP hosts, Add SNMP GET, GETNEXT and GETBULK queries to retrieve device from host MIBs (Management Information Base) using OIDs (Object Identifier): Running these workflows will add new items to the inventory.
Set policies to listen to trap events coming from SNMP hosts and to start remediation workflows</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure the AMQP plug-in to monitor vCloud Director</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/179-configure-the-amqp-plug-in.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/learn-vco/179-configure-the-amqp-plug-in.html</guid>
      <description>OK, so we told you about the great new plug-in that VMware has made available for vCO to work with AMQP, but now what? You&#39;ll need a couple things to get started before you can run off and code a bunch of cool workflows so let&#39;s step through this initial process...
Get and Install AMQP Server (RabbitMQ)Configure Publisher (vCloud Director 1.5)Configure Consumer (vCenter Orchestrator)Apply Policy Template to create new PolicyHow to create new Policy manuallyStarting the PolicyGet and install an AMQP server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infoblox announced a vCenter Orchestrator plug-in</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/187-infoblox-announced-a-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/187-infoblox-announced-a-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in.html</guid>
      <description>Quoting the Infoblox press-release:
Today at VMworld® 2011, Infoblox Inc. announced it is delivering a fully integrated plug-in for the VMware vCloud® Orchestrator community. Working with VMware vCloud Director™, the integrated solution provides automated IP addressing and related management capabilities in real-time as virtual machines are created.
As a result, the Infoblox plug-in accelerates private and public cloud deployment, simplifies management and bridges network and virtual IT team silos by enabling automated assignment of IP addresses to virtual machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware released the vCenter Orchestrator Plug-in SDK</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/183-vmware-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in-sdk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/183-vmware-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in-sdk.html</guid>
      <description>VMware released a software development kit allowing the creation of plug-in adapters for vCenter Orchestrator.&amp;nbsp;
 For the company having development resources it means that they can develop plug-ins for their private usage or for the 200.000+ vCenter customers. For end users this translates into the future availability of a lot more plug-ins.
Quoting the SDK page:
The VMware vCenter Orchestrator Plug-in SDK 4.2 is designed to jumpstart developers who are new to vCO plug-in development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware released the AMQP plug-in</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/177-vmware-released-the-amqp-plug-in.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/177-vmware-released-the-amqp-plug-in.html</guid>
      <description>VMware just released another new vCenter Orchestrator plug-in. The AMQP plug-in.
Quoting part of the release notes:
The VMware vCenter Orchestrator AMQP plug-in allows organizations to automatically trigger workflows based on AMQP messages. Advanced Message Queuing Protocol (AMQP) is a highly-scalable publish and subscribe message protocol that is increasingly used in cloud architectures. It is the default messaging protocol for vCloud Director 1.5. With the AMQP plug-in, organizations can define policies that automatically trigger specific workflows based on certain AMQP messages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vCenter Orchestrator new plug-ins covered in &#34;This week in virtualization&#34;</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/173-vcenter-orchestrator-new-plug-ins-covered-in-qthis-week-in-virtualizationq.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/173-vcenter-orchestrator-new-plug-ins-covered-in-qthis-week-in-virtualizationq.html</guid>
      <description>Brian Knudtson (@bknudtson) talks about new VMware vCenter Orchestrator plug-ins and the vCenter Converter 5.0 beta.
Listen to the podcast here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware is seeking for vCenter Orchestrator Plug-ins documentation feedback</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/171-vmware-is-seeking-for-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-ins-documentation-feedback.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/171-vmware-is-seeking-for-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-ins-documentation-feedback.html</guid>
      <description>If you develop workflows chances are that the plug-ins documentation is a very valuable resource for you. The VMware documentation team has written a short questionnaire about what is helpful or not in the existing guides and what you would like to see covered further. Please take a few minutes to answer here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware released the vCenter Orchestrator SOAP and REST Plug-ins</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/162-vmware-released-the-generic-soap-and-rest-plug-ins.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/162-vmware-released-the-generic-soap-and-rest-plug-ins.html</guid>
      <description>Today a major milestone has been achieved for vCenter Orchestrator.VMware released not one but two very useful plug-ins adapter:
SOAP is a protocol used to implement a web service typically used over HTTP and in combination with a service catalog (Web Service Description Language - WSDL pronounced wisdel). Examples of applications using SOAP are vCenter, vCenter Orchestrator, Lab Manager
REST is the technology behind the World Wide Web, leveraging HTTP verbs and URI to define resources and operations with stateless connections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware released the vCenter Orchestrator Plug-in for vCenter Update Manager</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/170-vmware-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in-for-vcenter-update-manager.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/170-vmware-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in-for-vcenter-update-manager.html</guid>
      <description>VMware just released another new vCenter Orchestrator plug-in. this time it is the turn to vCenter Update Manager to be orchestrated.
The main operations supported by this plug-in are:Creating a patch baseline: This is a patch repository containing the ESX host and VM patches attached to a vCenter. You can filter which patch to get from provider sites based on vendor, product, severity, update type, date.Attach a baseline to a set of vCenter objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware released the vCenter Orchestrator Plug-in for Microsoft Active Directory</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/154-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in-for-microsoft-active-directory-released.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/154-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in-for-microsoft-active-directory-released.html</guid>
      <description>Quoting the release notes : The VMware vCenter Orchestrator plug-in for Microsoft Active Directory allows organizations to automate the management of directory services tasks, particularly as they pertain to cloud provisioning use cases. For instance, the plug-in enables the automatic provisioning of vCloud Director organizations based on data retrieved from Active Directory. The plug-in also includes many administrative actions related to computers, organizations, user groups, and users, such as resetting passwords or adding users to a user group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Blog posts a Sample scenario for the Cisco UCS Manager plug-in!</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/146-vmware-blog-posts-a-sample-scenario-for-the-cisco-ucs-manager-plug-in.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/146-vmware-blog-posts-a-sample-scenario-for-the-cisco-ucs-manager-plug-in.html</guid>
      <description>As some of you may know, VMware recently launched an official vCenter Orchestrator blog! The team at VMware has put together a nice sample scenario post that walks you through the use of the Cisco UCS Manager plug-in. Be sure to stop by and check it out! To keep up on the posts there, feel free to follow their RSS Feed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware released the vCenter Orchestrator Plug-in for the Cisco UCS Manager</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/142-vmware-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in-for-the-cisco-ucs-manager.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/142-vmware-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in-for-the-cisco-ucs-manager.html</guid>
      <description>With this release vCenter Orchestrator is extending his reach in the automation of the cloud infrastructure with managing the physical infrastructure supporting it. For those that do not know yet it is installed as part of vCenter (starting with version 4.0) and usable at no additional cost. It is the only Orchestrator platform supporting full functionality of vCenter and vCloud Director. With the release of the Cisco UCS Manager the end to end provisioning of physical resources - virtual infrastructure - multi-tenant cloud Organizations, virtual Datacenters, vApps is now possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware released the vCenter Orchestrator Plug-in for vCloud Director</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/129-vmware-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in-for-vcloud-director.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/129-vmware-released-the-vcenter-orchestrator-plug-in-for-vcloud-director.html</guid>
      <description>Today VMware released the most complete automation solution for vCloud Director as a free download !
This is a plug-in for vCenter Orchestrator allowing to orchestrate vCloud Director (and not the other way around, vCD 1.01 does not have the ability to start an external process).
In terms of functionality the plug-in allows:
 Tenants to automate catalogs and vApp provisioning and decommissioning operations within their organization.Service providers to automate the configuration and management of the tenant organizations, their virtual data centers and their resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware vCloud Director vCO plug-in preview</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/104-vmware-vcloud-director-vco-plug-in-preview.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/104-vmware-vcloud-director-vco-plug-in-preview.html</guid>
      <description>The following videos are a preview of the upcoming VMware vCloud Director vCO plug-in. Since its release with vCenter 4, the main vCO plug-in has been for vCenter by fully supporting its API and providing several technical workflows. vCloud Director is already becoming VMware&#39;s next major API and as such will be fully supported by a vCO plug-in. The demonstration below shows examples on how to take advantage of this new plug-in and benefit from vCO powered automation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vCO VIX plug-in released !</title>
      <link>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/103-vco-vix-plug-in-released.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vcoteam.info/articles/newsflash/103-vco-vix-plug-in-released.html</guid>
      <description>We are proud to announce that vCO Team members and VMware labs today released a vCO (4.1) VIX plug-in for the VIX API version 1.10. If you wonder what VIX is here is an extract of the VIX landing page:
&#34;The VIX API allows you to write programs and scripts that automate virtual machine operations, as well as the guests within virtual machines. This API is high-level, easy to use, and practical for both script writers and application programmers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>